Guide to the Bill Brown Zine Collection, 1986-2011 and undated, bulk 1990-2005 RL.10072
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bill Brown zine collection, 1981-2011
1981-2011, bulk 1990-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Brown, Bill
RL.10072
4.8 Linear Feet 271 items
Bill Brown is a filmmaker, photographer, and zinester from Lubbock, Texas. His films explore the landscapes of North America, including the United States–Mexico border, North Dakota missile silos, and the Trans-Canada Highway, and have been exhibited at film festivals and museums around the world. He received a BFA from Harvard in 1992 and a MFA from CalArts in 1997. Brown is the author of a zine called Dream Whip as well as a novel on the underground in L.A., Saugus to the Sea. In January 2013, Bill Brown donated his personal collection of zines, comprising 186 titles and almost 250 issues in total. Although Brown never actively collected zines, he was always eager to barter and trade with other zine makers. The resulting collection includes zines spanning from the mid-1990s to the early 2000s. The zines are arranged alphabetically by title.
Provenance
The Bill Brown Zine Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in January 2013.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
In January 2013, Bill Brown donated his personal collection of zines, comprising 186 titles and almost 250 issues in total. Although Brown never actively collected zines, he was always eager to barter and trade with other zine makers. The resulting collection includes zines spanning from the mid-1990s to the early 2000s. The zines are arranged alphabetically by title.
Historical note
Bill Brown is a filmmaker, photographer, and zinester from Lubbock Texas. His films explore the landscapes of North America, including the United States–Mexico border, North Dakota missile silos, and the Trans-Canada Highway, and have been exhibited at film festivals and museums around the world. He received a BFA from Harvard in 1992 and a MFA from CalArts in 1997. Brown is the author of a zine called Dream Whip as well as a novel on the underground in L.A., Saugus to the Sea.
Race awareness -- United States; Underground press publications -- United States; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States.; Travel writing; Handicraft -- United States; Sexual orientation; Fan magazines; Bisexuality; Comic books, strips, etc.; Women's periodicals, American; Zines -- United States -- Periodicals; Zines -- Music -- United States; Women -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Self-publishing; Mail art -- United States; Punk culture -- United States; Counterculture.; Feminism -- United States; Interpersonal relations; Homosexuality.; Lesbianism -- United States; Anarchism; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Brown, Bill
- Bill Brown zine collection, 1981-2011; 5 Linear Feet
  - 2600: The Monthly Journal of the American Hacker, 1987., 1 Issue: Vol. 4, No. 10. Location: Middle Island, NY. (Box 1)
  - Abrupt Lane Edge, 1994., 1 Issue: 4. Location: Minneapolis, MN (Box 1)
  - AC Dickson's Guide to eBay PowerSelling, 2004., 1 Issue: 2004. Location: Portland, OR. (Box 1)
  - Airy Fairy Zine Distro, 1998., 1 Issue: 1998. Location: Dublin, Ireland (Box 1)
  - Alien., 1 Issue: 11. Location: Portland, OR. (Box 1)
  - Andy's Chair, 1994., 1 Issue: 3. Location: Berkeley, CA. (Box 1)
  - As long as there are slaughterhouses… then there will be battlefields., 1 Issue: 1992. Location: UK. (Box 1)
  - The Assassin and the Whiner, 1995., 1 Issue: 1. Location: Los Angeles, CA. (Box 1)
  - Autosuggestion., 2 Issues: 1-2. (Box 1)
  - The Baffler, 1998., 1 Issue: 11. Location: Chicago, IL. (Box 1)
  - Bamboo Girl, 2008., 1 Issue: 4. (Box 1)
  - Barnard Zine Library Zine, 2008., 1 Issue: 2008. Location: New York, NY. (Box 1)
  - Basement Children Zine Distro Catalog, 1998-1999., 2 Issues: Spring 1998, Spring 1999. Location: Chicago, IL. (Box 1)
  - Beer Powered Bicycle, 1999., 1 Issue: 1999: Location: Portland, OR. (Box 1)
  - Big Baby., 1 Issue. (Box 1)
  - The Blimp, 1995-1996., 3 Issues: 5-7. Location: Anacortes, WA. (Box 1)
  - Bloodshot Panic, 1985., 1 Issue: 4. (Box 1)
  - Blow My Colon, 1995., 1 Issue: 2. Location: Claremont, CA. (Box 1)
  - Book Your Own Fuckin' Life: a do it yourself resource guide, 1994-1999., 3 Issues: 3-4, 7. Location: Cicero, IL; San Francisco, CA. (Box 1)
  - Boredom, 1994., 1 Issue: 7. Location: Berkeley, CA. (Box 1)
  - Box Object, 1995., 1 Issue: 4. Location: [Doylestown, PA]. (Box 1)
  - Box of Fumes, 1994., 1 Issue: 1. Location: Fall River, MA. (Box 1)
  - Breakfast Served All Day, 1996-1998., 4 Issues: 2-5. Location: Minneapolis, MN. (Box 1)
  - Bugs and Drugs, 1993., 1 Issue: 3. Location: Bristol, UK. (Box 1)
  - Bummers and Gummers, 1994-1996., 2 Issues: 1.2, 3.9. Location: Lorane, OR. (Box 1)
  - Bunnyrabbit, 1996., 1 Issue: 7. Location: New York, NY. (Box 1)
  - Burn Collector., 1 Issue: 5. Location: Carrboro, NC. (Box 1)
  - Calder City [Calder City Revelations], 1993., 1 Issue: 3. (Box 2)
  - Certifiable, 1995., 1 Issue: 4. Location: Folsom, CA. (Box 2)
  - Charette's Eye View., 1 Issue: 9. Location: Fall River, MA. (Box 2)
  - Cheapskate Zine Distro, 1998., 1 Issue: 1. Location: Ferndale, MI. (Box 2)
  - Cinema Sewer, 2000., 1 Issue: 4. Vancouver, BC. (Box 2)
  - Cool Beans., 4 issues: 6, 8-9, 15. Location: San Francisco, CA. (Box 2)
  - A Crooked Stare, 1995., 1 Issue: 1995. Location: Bromley, Kent. (Box 2)
  - Cum., 2 Issues: 4-5. Location: Burnaby, BC. (Box 2)
  - Dawnwings, 1981., 1 Issue: 1981. Location: Council, ID. (Box 2)
  - Death and Tortillas, 1996., 1 Issue: 3. Location: Sacramento, CA. (Box 2)
  - The Devil in the Dishes, 1994., 1 Issue: 2. Location: Berkeley, CA. (Box 2)
  - Dirty Plotte, 1992., 1 Issue: 5. Location: Seattle, WA. (Box 2)
  - The Disembodied Brain., 1 Issue. (Box 2)
  - Distracted by the stars, 1998., 1 Issue: 5. Location: Chicago, IL. (Box 2)
  - Diving for Aliens., 1 Issue. Location: Bromley, UK. (Box 2)
  - Doochisuck, 1994-1995., 6 Issues: 1-6. Location: Seattle, WA. (Box 2)
  - Doris, 1 Issue: 13. Asheville, NC. (Box 2)
  - Dreaming Spires and Flaming Tyres., 1 Issue. Location: Oxford, UK. (Box 2)
  - Drew, 1996., 1 Issue: 4. Location: Berkeley, CA. (Box 2)
  - Dynamite Head, 1995., 1 Issue: 1995. (Box 2)
  - E. G. Smith Distribution Catalog, 1996., 1 Issue: Winter-Spring 1996. Location: Columbus, OH. (Box 2)
  - Ecurb, 1994., 2 Issues: Feb. 1994, Sept. 1994. Location: Anaheim, CA. (Box 2)
  - Eightball, 1989-1993., 4 Issues: 1, 9-11. Location: Seattle, WA. (Box 2)
  - Environmental Fax Orgy, 1993., 1 Issue: 1993. Location: St Paul, MN. (Box 2)
  - The Excluded Middle: an Esoteric Journal for the Masses, 1994., 1 Issue: 4. Location: Los Angeles, CA. (Box 2)
  - Factsheet5: the final word on the zine revolution, 1998., 1 Issue: 64. Location: San Francisco, CA. (Box 3)
  - The Family Album, 1995., 1 Issue: 1995. (Box 3)
  - Fantastique!, 1 Issue. Location: Exeter, UK. (Box 3)
  - Fascism, 1996., 1 Issue: Jan. 1996. Location: Titusville, FL. (Box 3)
  - Fern, 1995., 2 Issues: 10-11. Location: Milwaukee, WI. (Box 3)
  - Fifty-Ninth St., 2 Issues: 2-3. Location: New York, NY. (Box 3)
  - Flex Fest: Florida Experimental Film/Video Festival, Nov. 2005., 1 Issue: Nov. 2005. Location: Gainesville, FL. (Box 3)
  - Footloose Journal, 1999, 1 Issue: 1. Location: Swansea, UK. (Box 3)
  - Free American Newsmagazine., 2 Issues: [1995], Aug. 1998. Location: Bingham, NM. (Box 3)
  - Friends & Family, 1996/1997., 1 Issue: 1996/1997. Location: Austin, TX. (Box 3)
  - From the Diane Files, 1992., 1 Issue: 1. Location: Cleveland Hights, OH. (Box 3)
  - Fucktooth, 1993-1996., 2 Issues: 7, 20. Location: Mayfield Hts, OH. (Box 3)
  - Garbles, 1993., 1 Issue: 7. Canterbury, Kent, UK. (Box 3)
  - Geist: The Canadian Magazine of Ideas and Culture, 1998., 2 Issues: 29-30. Vancouver, BC. (Box 3)
  - Guff, 2005., 2 Issues: 2-3. New York, NY. (Box 3)
  - Hairy Scab, 1995., 1 Issue: 4. Tucson, AZ. (Box 3)
  - Hell Yes I Cheated., 1 Issue: 1. Blooming Prairie, MN. (Box 3)
  - Helvetica, 1997., 2 Issues: 4-5. Chicago, IL. (Box 3)
  - .honey., 1 Issue: 1. St Paul, MN. (Box 3)
  - Horse., 2 Issues: 2-3. Berkeley, CA. (Box 3)
  - How to Get From Los Angeles to Istanbul on one bag of peanuts., 1 Issue. (Box 3)
  - I, 1995., 1 Issue: 11. Vancouver, BC. (Box 3)
  - I am the Thumb Tack, 1993., 1 Issue: Dec. 1993. Warrensburg, MO. (Box 3)
  - Icarus was right, 1996., 2 Issues: 2-3. San Diego, CA. (Box 3)
  - Ichthyoelectroanalgesia., 1 Issue: 1. Columbia, MO. (Box 3)
  - I Fell Down, 1994., 1 Issue: 1994. Portsmouth, NH. (Box 4)
  - I Like Your Shoes., 1 Issue: 1. Piedmont, CA. (Box 4)
  - I'm Johnny and I don't Give a Fuck, 1998., 1 Issue: 3. Vancouver, BC. (Box 4)
  - Insipid Love, 1998., 1 Issue: 10. Vancouver, BC. (Box 4)
  - Jeff's Austin Diary, 2000-2011., 1 Issue. New York, NY. (Box 4)
  - The Jekyll and Hyde Years., 1 Issue: 1. South Haven, MN. (Box 4)
  - Judge Parker's Penis, 1996., 1 Issue: 1. Fort Smith, AR. (Box 4)
  - Juxtsuppose, 1994-1995., 2 Issues: 1-2. N. Vancouver, BC. (Box 4)
  - Kent's Zine, 1995., 1 Issue: 1995. Madison, WI. (Box 4)
  - Kylie Proudctions Catalogue, 1998., 1 Issue: Nov. 1998. Wandsworth, UK. (Box 4)
  - The Last Prom, 1993., 1 Issue: 2. Burbank, CA. (Box 4)
  - Last Train, 1995., 2 Issues: Spring 1995; Oct. 1995. Hyattsville, MD; Dover, NJ. (Box 4)
  - The Lee Bros. Boiled Peanuts Catalogue, 1995-1999., 3 Issues: 2-3, 9. Charleston, SC. (Box 4)
  - Let's Get Back to School., 1 Issue: 1993 Winter Supplement. Port Townsend, WA. (Box 4)
  - Letter to a friend., 1 Issue. New Orleans, LA. (Box 4)
  - Life After Birth, 1993., 1 Issue: 1993. Blackpool, UK. (Box 4)
  - Life is a Joke., 1 Issue: 10. San Francisco, CA. (Box 4)
  - Lila, 2004-2005., 1 Issue: 3. Flagstaff, AZ. (Box 4)
  - livingProof, 2005., 1 Issue: 4. Chicago, IL. (Box 4)
  - Lost Armadillos in Heat., 2 Issues: 6/7, 9. Austin TX. (Box 4)
  - Manic D Press Catalog, 1994., 1 Issue: 1994. San Francisco, CA. (Box 4)
  - Martin's Rant 'n' Roll., 1 Issue. (Box 4)
  - Maximum RockNRoll, 1998., 1 Issue: 186. San Francisco, CA. (Box 4)
  - The Melody Haunts My Reverie, 1993., 1 Issue: 3. Tiverton, UK. (Box 4)
  - MFP Comics, 1998., 1 Issue: 1. (Box 4)
  - Misuse/Numb., 1 Issue: 5/6. Carlton, AU. (Box 4)
  - Moonlight Chronicles, 1998-2004., 3 Issues: 24-25, 42. Joseph, OR. (Box 4)
  - Mudflap., 2 Issues. San Francisco, CA. (Box 5)
  - My Cat Patches., 1 Issue: 4. Tecumseh, ON. (Box 5)
  - My Private Life., 1 Issue. Los Angeles, CA. (Box 5)
  - [New Bick's Sandwich Stackers]., 1 Issue: 1. (Box 5)
  - Nomo-the-Zine, 1995., 1 Issue: Feb. 1995. Bellingham, WA. (Box 5)
  - No One Likes the Yo-Yo, 1995., 1 Issue. (Box 5)
  - Octojello, 1996., 1 Issue: 2. Portland, OR. (Box 5)
  - Oh Ye of Little Faith, 1995., 1 Issue: 1995. Valencia, CA. (Box 5)
  - Okie-dokie Distro., 1 Issue: 2. Oklahoma City, OK. (Box 5)
  - The Orange Couch., 3 Issues: 2-3, 8. Milwaukee, WI. (Box 5)
  - Overthrow, 1986., 1 Issue: 8.2. New York, NY. (Box 5)
  - Pants That Don't Fit., 1 Issue: 7. San Jose, CA. (Box 5)
  - Playground Liberation Front Stickers, 1999., 1 Issue: 1999. Vancouver, BC. (Box 5)
  - Plotz, 1998., 2 Issues: 9-10. New York, NY. (Box 5)
  - Plotz lite., 1 Issue: 5. New York, NY. (Box 5)
  - Po, 1993-1994., 4 Issues: 11, 15-17. Portland, ME. (Box 5)
  - Pony up, donkey down., 1 Issue: 1. Vancouver, BC. (Box 5)
  - Pop Boffin., 1 Issue: 2. Vancouver, BC. (Box 5)
  - Popcornhead, 2005., 1 Issue. (Box 5)
  - Puddin, 1998., 2 Issues: 1-2. Brooklyn, NY. (Box 5)
  - Punchline, 1990., 1 Issue: 7. San Francisco, CA. (Box 5)
  - Punk Planet, 1997., 1 Issue: 17. Chicago, IL; E. Mansing, MI. (Box 5)
  - Quench., 1 Issue: 2. Portland, OR. (Box 6)
  - Ration, 2003., 1 Issue: 3. San Francisco, CA. (Box 6)
  - Reasonably Martian's., 1 Issue: 5. Wilmington, NC. (Box 6)
  - Recipes for Disaster., 1 Issue. (Box 6)
  - Remnants, 1995., 1 Issue: 1995. (Box 6)
  - Ring of Fire, 1997., 1 Issue: 2. Seattle, WA. (Box 6)
  - Rush Kill, 1995., 2 Issues: 1-2. Boothbay Harbor, ME. (Box 6)
  - Salt for Slugs, 1998., 1 Issue: 2.4. Austin, TX. (Box 6)
  - Sanitary and Ship, 2005., 1 Issue: 2005. Chicago, IL. (Box 6)
  - Scenery, 2005., 1 Issue: 19. Providence, RI. (Box 6)
  - Shampoop., 3 Issues: 1-3. Lake Forest, IL. (Box 6)
  - Shattered Mind, 1995., 1 Issue: 7. Martin, TN. (Box 6)
  - Sick., 1 Issue. Cleveland Heights, OH. (Box 6)
  - Sister Friend, 2004., 1 Issue: 16. Fairview Heights, IL. (Box 6)
  - Skinny Zine, 1 Issue: 12. Oklahoma City, OK. (Box 6)
  - Slouch, 1993., 1 Issue: 1. Falmouth, Cornwall, UK. (Box 6)
  - Slumber., 2 Issues: 6, 8. Cazadero, CA. (Box 6)
  - Sobstory?, 1 Issue: 6. San Francisco, CA. (Box 6)
  - Something, 1995., 1 Issue: 2. Bath, UK. (Box 6)
  - Something for Nothing, 1 issue. Masillon, OH; Duluth, MN. (Box 6)
  - Son of the Ultimate Comics Catalogue, 1992., 1 Issue: 1992. Seattle, WA. (Box 6)
  - Souther comics, 1995., 1 Issue: 4. Modesto, CA. (Box 6)
  - Spaghetti Dinner & Dancing, 1998., 1 Issue: 12. Missoula, MT. (Box 6)
  - Sperm Sells., 1 Issue: 3. Goleta, CA. (Box 6)
  - Stand in the Back, 1999., 1 Issue. Fredonia, NY. (Box 7)
  - [Star]., 1 Issue: 1994-1995. (Box 7)
  - Stardrift, 1994., 1 Issue: 1. New Brunswick, NJ. (Box 7)
  - Stay as You Are, 1996-1998., 3 Issues: 1-3. N. Vancouver, BC, Canada. (Box 7)
  - Sterile Vision, 1997., 2 Issues: 2-3. St. John's, Canada. (Box 7)
  - Stiff and Crusty, 1996., 1 Issue: Vol. 1, No. 2. Seattle, WA. (Box 7)
  - Stop go destroy, 2003-2004., 2 Issues: 5-6. Oakland, CA. (Box 7)
  - Stratosphere, 1998., 2 Issues: 3-4. Edison, NJ. (Box 7)
  - Streetlamp Warfare., 1 Issue. (Box 7)
  - Subliminal Tattoos, 1996, 1 Issue: 8. Vancouver, WA. (Box 7)
  - Super monster, 1999., 1 Issue: 10. Griffith, IN. (Box 7)
  - [Sweethearts]., 1 Issue. (Box 7)
  - Tail Spins, 1997-2001., 2 Issues: 29, 34. Evanston, IL. (Box 7)
  - Teenage Gang Debs, 1992., 1 Issue: 4. Bethesda, MD. (Box 7)
  - Texas., 2 Issues: 2-2.5. Northampton, UK. (Box 7)
  - Things, 1993., 1 Issue. Denver, CO. (Box 7)
  - Thirst Magazine., 1 Issue: Spring/Summer 2001. New York, NY. (Box 7)
  - This anatomy is music., 1 Issue: 1. Leominster, MA. (Box 7)
  - Three Sheets to the Wind, 1999., 1 Issue: 4. Portland, OR. (Box 7)
  - Tools of the Trade., 1 Issue. (Box 8)
  - Travelling Shoes, 1998., 1 Issue: 2. New Haven, CT. (Box 8)
  - Turtletown Times, 1994., 1 Issue: Vol. 1, No. 29. Linda Vista, CA. (Box 8)
  - Ugly, 1994., 3 Issues: 3. San Francisco, CA. (Box 8)
  - Unterview., 1 Issue. Victoria, BC. (Box 8)
  - Vampire Schoolgirl., 1 Issue: 8. Nolalu, ON. (Box 8)
  - Villa Villa Cola, 1998., 1 Issue: 4. La Mesa, CA. (Box 8)
  - Waaaa., 1 Issue: 1. Austin, TX. (Box 8)
  - The Wacky Adventures of Sally Schramm, 1997., 1 Issue. (Box 8)
  - We went to San Antonio to see…, 1 Issue. San Antonio, TX. (Box 8)
  - Wow Cool, 1997., 1 Issue: Spring 1997. Berkeley, CA. (Box 8)
  - Yazuka, 1997., 1 Issue: 9. Wilmington, DE. (Box 8)
  - Yob, 1996., 1 Issue: 4. Seattle, WA. (Box 8)
  - You Bet Your Sweet Ass I'm a Turtle., 1 Issue: 2. San Francisco, CA. (Box 8)
  - You Live For the Fight When That's All That You've Got, 2006., 1 Issue: 1. Brighton, MA. (Box 8)
  - Zine Distro Zine, 1998., 1 Issue: Summer 1998. Ann Arbor, MI. (Box 8)
  - Zineguide, Fall/Winter 2001., 1 Issue: 5. Evanston, IL. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence and ephemera. (Box 8)